Finding Aid for the Sam Fleming Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Sam Fleming Papers
2007
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0143
2.1 Linear Feet
Biographical Note
Samuel Milton Fleming was born on April 29, 1908 in Franklin, Tennessee. He graduated from Battle Ground Academy in 1924 and from Vanderbilt University in 1928. Fleming served in active duty with the U.S. Naval Reserve from 1942-1945. After college he worked for a time in New York and then came to Third National Bank in Nashville in 1931 and by 1950 was appointed president where he served until his retirement in 1970. He was active in many areas of business and commerce in Nashville and in committee, fundraising, and other charitable work.
He served on the Board of Trust of Vanderbilt University from 1952 until 1981 and as its Chairman from 1975 to 1981. He was Chairman of the Board of Trust at the time of the merger with George Peabody College for Teachers in 1979 and as such played an important role in bringing the two institutions together. He also was instrumental in the creation of the Owen Graduate School of Management in 1969 and for the creation of the Blair School of Music at Vanderbilt in 1981.
Sam Fleming held many civic memberships and served in leadership roles as community activist and philanthropist in Nashville and nationally, and was an elder of the First Presbyterian Church.
He was honored at Vanderbilt with the dedication of the Fleming Yard on November 6, 1987.
Yours to Count On: a biography of Nashville banker extraordinaire Sam M. Fleming by Ridley Wills, II was published by Vanderbilt University Press in 2007.
He was married to Josephine Cliffe Fleming who preceded him in death and then to Valerie Ellis Fleming. He and Josephine had two children, Joanne and Daniel. Sam Fleming died on January 21, 2000.
Sam Fleming was a great patron of the Vanderbilt Library and in addition to donating a number of important Bibles from the late 16th and early 17th centuries ( the Geneva version of the so-called “Breeches” Bible, reference to Genesis 3:7), in his will he endowed the Sam Fleming Southern Civilization Collection in Special Collections, a growing collection of books on the history, culture, literature, and biography of the South since 1865.
Scope and Content Note
These papers five Hollinger boxes ( 2.1 linear feet), flat box and accompanying woodcut prints are made up primarily of materials relating to Sam Fleming and Vanderbilt and include items from his time as an undergraduate (1924-1928), his tenure on the Board of Trust (1952-1981), the Athletic program and building of the new stadium, speeches and remarks by Fleming and others, and the Merger of Vanderbilt with Peabody College in 1979, when Fleming was chairman of the Board of Trust.This collection also includes nine items, historic documents or concerning historic documents, given by Stanley Horn to Sam Fleming, dating from 1617 to 1958.
There are also typescripts of Supper at the Maxwell House with author’s notes by Alfred Leland Crabb as well as an interview with Crabb in Nashville! magazine. There is a box of 28 official documents signed by Tennessee Governors during the years 1808 – 1930.
- File Listing
- 1924-1928 Sam Fleming’s undergraduate years at Vanderbilt
  - Pictures of environs of Nashville from the 1897 Exposition (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Photograph of the football team (c. 192? ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Football cheers (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Vanderbilt Hustler, Oct. 2, 1925, vol.xxxvii (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Football program—Auburn vs. Vanderbilt at Birmingham, Alabama, Nov. 14, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Program: “Know Tennessee” oratorical contest, 3-20-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Program: Annual Dialectic-Philosophic Debate, 12-3-1926 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Paper—Debate—Tax-Exempt-Securities (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Student papers by Fleming—Public Speaking, 12-12-1926 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - History, 4-15-1927 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 1925 Rules for the Guidance of Students and Instructors; 1927 Football schedule; small felt VU pendant (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 1924-1928 Student Records—schedule and fees (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 1927 Athletic (Track) Record Book (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Athletic Association—Requisitions of expenses for the Track Team, 1927-28 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Vanderbilt Alumnus,”Football Number” vol.XIII, Nov.-Dec. 1927, No.2 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Program: City-County Boys Track and Field Meet, May 4, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 1928 Commencement Program (5) and Commencement Day ticket (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Official Blank Examination Book (192_) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Other Vanderbilt University events
  - Programs (2)—Fugitive Reunion May 1956—Poetry Reading—both are signed by Robert Penn Warren, Merrill Moore, Allen Tate, Donald Davidson, John Crowe Ransom (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Alexander Heard—Correspondence Re: Chancellorship at VU, June 13, 1962 --June 29, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - “Vanderbilt Names a New Chancellor”—N. Y. Herald Tribune, 6-17-62 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Vanderbilt in Summer, General Information, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Centennial of the University, Oct. 3, 1975—“Yale President to Speak at VU” from The Tennessean; Invitation (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - “Dinner Honors New President of VU Board,” Nashville Banner, May 3, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - “Vanderbilt Board Members and Wives Entertained at Parties,” Nashville Banner, Oct. 3, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Centennial of the University, Oct. 3, 1975—Programs; Vanderbilt Gazette, Oct.1, 1975; Vanderbilt Today, November 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence and materials re: Portrait of Chancellor Heard by Aaron Shiker, July 23, 1975—Nov. 6, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Memorabilia “Groundbreaking Vanderbilt University Hospital July 6, 1977” Acrylic Paperweight (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence between Chancellor Heard and Anne Marie and Thomas B. Walker, Jr. concerning million dollar gift of the Walkers to Library Fund for the VU Owen School of Management, December 15, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Audio tape, Chancellor Heard, content and date? (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - “Sam Fleming is new Board of Trust Head.. .” Vanderbilt Today, Vol. 15, no.3, July, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “New VU Divinity Head Sees ‘Exciting Times’” (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Calendar “Vanderbilt A Century of Growth”, 1974-75 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “Board President believes in VU” Hustler, vol. 87, no.5, Sept. 9, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Vanderbilt Hustler, Feb. 10, 13,17,1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “Vanderbilt Picketed in Apartheid Protest” N.Y. Times, Feb. 15, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Articles from the Vanderbilt Register (5-21-1982) and Hustler (4-27-1982) on the Chancellor search (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Neill Sanders, Dean of Admissions, August 4, 1989, articles and note (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Vanderbilt Medicine, vol. 14, no. 1, Spring/Summer 1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Vanderbilt Magazine, vol. 79, no.3, Summer 1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Photocopy of a letter from Thomas F. Frist, Jr. to John R. Hall resigning from the Vanderbilt Board of Trust, September 17, 1997 and letters in reply Sept. 22, 1997, Sept. 23, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - “Stahlman Gives VU Scholarship” (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Remarks, Speeches, and other notes
  - Speech by Sam M. Fleming at a convocation at Florida Southern College, March 9, 1962; letter from Madison Sarratt to Sam Fleming, Jan. 8, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Remarks by Sam Fleming to open $55 million VU campaign, July 1, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Speech materials—The Bulletin of Miss Porter’s School ( Farmington, Connecticut), Spring 1975 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Speech materials for Sam Fleming—Vanderbilt Hustler, September 16, 1975; Vanderbilt Gazette, December 1, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Sam Fleming for the Board of Trust opening remarks for the program for the Centennial of the University, Oct. 3, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Remarks by Sam Fleming for Awards Luncheon honoring Dr. Frank Pittman, April 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Remarks by Fleming at Installation dinner for Joe B. Wyatt as Chancellor of Vanderbilt University, Feb. 23, 1983; Program for the Installation of Joe Wyatt as Chancellor of Vanderbilt University,Thursday, Feb. 24, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - “Opportunity Plentiful Here: Fleming,” Nashville Banner (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Remarks by Sam Fleming, Chancellor Heard, Chancellor Wyatt, and others at the 1987 Dedication of Fleming Yard; Vanderbilt Today, vol. 27, No. 1, Winter 1988 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Remarks by Chancellor Alexander Heard to the Consortium of Universities, Jan. 17, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Remarks by Chancellor Alexander Heard at the Graduation Exercises, Southwestern at Memphis, May 31, 1975, “One Educational World” (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Remarks of Chancellor Alexander Heard at Commencement, May 17, 1978 in the Vanderbilt Gazette, No. 103, June 2, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - “Remarks of Chancellor Alexander Heard at Commencement, May 11, 1979 in the Vanderbilt Gazette, No. 112, June 1, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Remarks of Chancellor Heard to new students, August 25, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Remarks of Chancellor Alexander Heard at Commencement, May 9, 1980” in the Vanderbilt Gazette, No. 121, June 1, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Remarks of Chancellor Alexander Heard to the welcoming convocation for new students, Memorial Gymnasium, August 23, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - “ A Statement by Chancellor Heard” in the Vanderbilt Gazette, Dec. 18, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Speech by William S. Vaughn “A View of the Establishment” Baccalaureate Address at Vanderbilt, May 14, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - “Eliminating Racial Barriers at Vanderbilt University” by Harvie Branscomb with letter dated, July 27, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - “My Story of Vanderbilt” by Ben Austin, typescript (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Tribute to Dr. Josh Billings (Frederic Tremaine Billings) VU School of Medicine (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - “A Brief History of Vanderbilt University 1872—1982” by Robert A. McGaw and Reba Wilcoxin (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - VUMC Reporter, Friday, Oct. 17, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Guest List—Vanderbilt University Hospital Topping and Ceremony, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Vanderbilt Register, May 1, 1981 “Board of Trust Elects David K. Wilson as Chairman” (with photo of Sam Fleming) (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Poems “The Roaring Twenties” by Charles E. Dobb; “To Our Nurses” Harvie and Margaret Branscomb, May 15, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Battle Ground Academy Board of Trustees—Headmaster’s Report, Nov. 11, 1993 to members of the BGA Board of Trust (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - “6 joining VU Board of Trust as new members...” Tennessean April 27, 1997 (Joanne Fleming Hayes) (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Obituary—Sam Fleming—“Former VU board president Sam Fleming mourned” in The Reporter, Jan. 28, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Vanderbilt Athletics and the new Stadium
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, Nov. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, Nov. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic progam, Nov.-Dec. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, Dec. 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, Jan. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, Feb. 1972 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, March 1972 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, papers, etc. concerning the athletic program, April 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence re: Vanderbilt athletic program, Nov. 1971 to Faculty: Winston L. King; R. Chris Hassel; John Gaventa; Harold G. Maier (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence re: Vanderbilt Athletic Program—Karl Haury, Nov. 16, 1971; Joe and Joy White, Nov. 23, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence re: Vanderbilt Athletic Program, November 1971—Chancellor Heard to Eugene Higgins; Jerry Watson; Arthur Earls; Carlin Rolfe; J. William Douglas (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - “Vanderbilt” in The Tennessean Monday 11/1/1971; “ The Vandy Plan Intrigues Conference” (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Athletic Program—Re: Meeting with students Dec. 2, 1971; Meeting of Executive Committee, March 7, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence re: Physical Education curriculum, March 1972; Chancellor Heard to Harold Maier with replies (5 separate documents) (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Preliminary Agenda, Board of Trust, May 5-6, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Report from the Special Trustee Committee on Athletics, May 1972 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - “Sidelines—A Major Breakthough” by Fred Russell in the Nashville Banner, Friday May 5, 1972 with Preliminary Report Special Trustee Committee on Athletics (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - “NCAA Approves VU—Peabody Athletic Tieup” Nashville Banner, Friday May 5, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence re: Athletic Program May 10, 1972 from John Bibb, Sports Editor, The Tennessean (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence re: Athletic Program, May 17, 1972 from Lane Abernathy, President VU Alumni Association (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence and document on VU Athletics, May 22, 1972—Vice chancellor Rob Roy Purdy to Sam Fleming (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence re: Vanderbilt Athletic Program—Bill Pace, Director of Athletics and Head Football Coach, Dec. 19, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - “ Clay Stapleton Gets Vanderbilt A.D. Post” by Fred Russell in the Nashville Banner, Feb. 8, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Vanderbilt University Medical Center Energy Conservation Study and Report, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence and Reports, 1977—Stadium Design and Construction (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Memorandum, Sept. 26, 1977; Finch Heery Official Study—Vanderbilt Stadium, Sept., 1977; Drawings by the local firm of William Elliston and Assoc.—Feasibility Study for Additions, Nov. 25, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence re: Vanderbilt Stadium, August, 29, 1977, William Elliston and Assoc.; Dudley Field Feasibility Study, Nov. 25, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Minutes, Executive Committee; Board of Trusst, VU, 9-13-1977; Possible Football Revenue Loss; Amortization Schedule; Letter re: Municipal Stadium Study Committee, Oct. 4, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Vanderbilt University/ Peabody College Merger in 1979
  - “Bruce Ryburn Payne and the New Peabody College” by A.L.Crabb, Professor of Education, George Peabody College. Reprinted from Southern Association Quarterly November, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - “Brief Historical Facts about Peabody” in The Peabody Reflector, July, August, 1968, vol.XLI, no. 4 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Warranty deed, September 30, 1976—University School of Nashville (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, February 22, 1979—April 27, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, April 1979 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence— with Frank Mayborn, August 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence—about the School of Music (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence—Chancellor Heard to others concerning the Music School with Statement, July 31, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Draft—Memorandum of Understanding Relating to the Merger of Vanderbilt University and George Peabody College for Teachers; confidential cover letter, April 23, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Draft—Memorandum of Understanding Relating to the Merger of Vanderbilt University and George Peabody College for Teachers, April 25, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Remarks by Chancellor Heard of Vanderbilt to the Board of Trustees of George Peabody College for Teachers, April 27, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Agenda for the meeting of the Board of Trust, April 27-28, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Exhibit papers relating to the Merger in 1979 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - “Bragg Hits Peabody, TSU Plan” Jan. 15, 1979; “Peabody May Leave State if Merger Fails” in the Tennessean (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - “Vandy-Peabody Tie-up in Peril” in The Tennessean, February 14, 1979 by John Bibb (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - “Vanderbilt and Peabody to Merge” in Vanderbilt Today, vol.19, No. 1, April 1979; “Colleges told that survival will require some cutbacks “in the N.Y.Times, April 17, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - “Merger Promotes Music, Art Debate” in Vanderbilt Hustler, Tuesday April 24, 1979, Vol. 90, No. 56 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - “Hands Across the Street: Peabody –Her Bricks, Her People” by Terry Dugan, Versus, April 1979 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - “The Peabody Merger: Swiftness Breaks Confusion” by Pat Willard in Versus, September 1979 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Program for the Peabody College Roundtable Dinner, October 7, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Photographs
  - Photocopies of pictures appearing in Vanderbilt publications requested by Charles Cook for his tribute to Mr. Fleming on, March 2, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Harrell Meadors, Charles Boyle, Frazer Edmondson in front of S.A.E House, 100 23rd Avenue, Nashville, Tn, Spring 1928 with accompanying letter from J. Bayard Boyle, December 4, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - SAE Basketball team, Sam Fleming top row, center right, from, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Commodore, p. 269; Battle Ground Academy (Franklin, TN) team 1924, Sam Fleming, 3rd from left top row (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Sam and Josephine Fleming,Liz and Anderson Spickard, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Members of the VU Board of Trust, 1952-1953—identified on back of the photo (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Class of 1928 taken May 20, 1978—50th Reunion, members identified (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Alexander Heard and Walter Fields, III, Oct. 25, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Alexander Heard and Sam Fleming, April 1981 upon Fleming’s retirement (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Class Reunion, Sam Fleming home, May 22, 1998—members present—Malcolm Gibbs, Florence Eskind Zucker, Grace Frierson Walker, Jack DeWitt, D.R. Lewis, William Hobby, Sam Fleming (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Grace and Ted Walker (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Historic Documents given to Sam Fleming by Stanley Horn (list included)
  - Legal Document with wax seal, 1617 (parchment) Charter (?) from Alexander Chalmer to Robert (?) Cargill (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Receipt, July 19, 1806, signed by Andrew Jackson, to John Childress for $400 and William P. Anderson for $347 in settlement of a lawsuit (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Land Grant, State of Tennessee (includes the embossed state seal), 1808, to James Robertson, assignee of Samuel Jackson, for 125 acres in Dickson County, signed by John Sevier, governor (fragile) (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Invitation, June 25, 1827, to the Anniversary Ball to be held on July 4 in Nashville to celebrate the anniversary of American Independence. (invitation is addressed to “The Misses Greens”) (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Check, December 13, 1834, for $3000 from H. R.W. Hill (?) to Andrew Jackson. presented by Jackson for payment on, February 24, 1835 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Stock Certificate, October 22, 1867, for 100 shares in the Emory Iron and Coal Mining Co., Knoxville, Tenn. purchased by William Small for $10,000. (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Appointment, 1870, of New Trustees under Settlement and Marriage of Mr. Edmund Walker and Emma Eliza his wife, and Post-nuptial Settlement of Equity of Redemption of Freehold Premises at Leytonstone, Essex. ( a very complex oversize legal document with all kinds of details about land holdings, etc.) (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Letter, typed, from Stanley Horn to Sam M. Fleming, February 20, 1958, summarizing the history of the seal of the Confederate States of America. (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Typed note the history of the CSA seal (undated) (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Alfred Leland Crabb (1884-1979) Nashville author and Peabody College professor
  - Typescript—Supper at the Maxwell House, Book I, with author’s notes (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Typescript—Supper at the Maxwell House, Book II, with author’s notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Supper at the Maxwell House, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Nashville!—“Crabb’s Love Affair” by Dennis Loyd, October 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- 28 Official Documents signed by Tennessee Governors, 1808-1930
  - Signature of John Sevier, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1796 – 1801, 1803 -1809; dated October 20, 1808 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Signature of William Blount, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1790 – 1796, 1809 – 1815; dated December 18, 1813 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Signature of Joseph McMinn, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1815 -1821; dated July 15, 1817 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Signature of William Carroll, Governor of the State of Tennnessee, 1821 -1827; dated June 8, 1822 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Signature of Newton Cannon, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1835 – 1839; dated September 1836 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Signature of James C. Jones, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1841 – 1845; dated July 1, 1844 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Signature of Neill S. Brown, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1847 – 1849; dated May 21, 1849 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Signature of William Trousdale, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1849 – 1851, this is dated September 17, 1851 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Signature of William B. Campbell, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1851 – 1853; dated July 18, 1853 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Signature of William G. Brownlow, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1865 – 1869; dated September 10, 1867 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Signature of DeWitt Clinton Senter, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1869 – 1871; dated May 11, 1870 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Signature of John C. Brown, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1871 – 1875; dated September 3, 1874 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Signature of James D. Porter, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1875 – 1879, dated September 28, 1878 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Signature of Albert S. Marks, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1879 – 1881; dated November 24, 1880 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Signature of Alvin Hawkins, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1881 – 1883; dated August 14, 1882 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Signature of William B. Bate, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1883 – 1887; dated February 22, 1883 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Signature of John P. Buchanan, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1891 – 1893; dated November 19, 1891 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Signature of Peter Turney, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1893 -1897; dated November 17, 1893 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Signature of Robert Love Taylor, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1887 – 1891 and 1897 – 1899; dated October 10, 1898 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Signature of Benton McMillan, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1899 – 1903; dated August 4, 1900 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Signature of James B. Frazier, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1903 – 1905; dated August 22, 1903 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Signature of John I. Cox, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1905 -1907; dated August 27, 1906 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Signature of Malcolm R. Patterson, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1907 – 1911; dated February 15, 1909 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Signature of Ben W. Hooper, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1911 – 1915; dated March 30, 1912 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Signature of Tom C. Rye, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1915 – 1919; dated November 15, 1916 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Signature of A. H. Roberts, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1919 – 1921; dated May 7, 1919 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Signature of Henry H. Horton, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1927 – 1933; dated March 16, 1929 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Signature of Gordon Browning, Governor of the State of Tennessee, 1937 – 1939 and 1949 – 1953; dated June 5, 1930 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- 28 Official Documents signed by Tennessee Governors, 1808-1930
  - Name index and folder number: (Box 6)
    Bate, William B., folder 16
    Blount, William, folder 2
    Brown, John C., folder 12
    Brown, Neill S., folder 7
    Browning, Gordon, folder 28